（鈴羽(すずは)）まゆ姉さん
こんな所にいたんだ
So this is where you've been, Mayu.
Suzu...
（まゆり）鈴(すず)ちゃん
Dad and the others are looking for you.
（鈴羽）
父さんたちが捜してた
They said they're about to kick off the operation.
もうすぐ
作戦開始の時間だって
まゆ姉さん？
Mayu?
What if...
（まゆり）もし…
What if back then...
（まゆり）
もしも あのとき―
Had I reached out this hand,
この手を
伸ばしていたら―
would this future be any different?
この未来は変わったのかな
That day, if my Hikoboshi had come back
to life, it might have changed everything.
（まゆり）あの日
私の彦星(ひこぼし)が復活していれば―
全ては変わっていたかもしれない
What if back then...
もしも あのとき―
この手を伸ばしていたら…
...had I reached out this hand...
Christmas
Sale
12/05
to 12/25
You are passing down,
sinking through your past...
（医師）
あなたは過去へ降りてゆきます
Deeper...
どんどん どんどん降りてゆくと
光が見えます
As you go even deeper, you then see a light.
What color is that light?
光は何色ですか？
Red...
（岡部(おかべ)）赤…
Within that light stands
someone important to you.
（医師）その光の中に
あなたの大切な人が立っています
Is that person your family?
あなたの家族ですか？
いや…
No...
Then a friend, or perhaps a lover?
（医師）では友人？　恋人ですか？
We're not even friends.
（岡部）友人ですらない
She and I are—
俺と あいつは…
Ah! Okarin!
（まゆり）あっ オカリン！
What gives? I said you
didn't have to wait for me.
（岡部）
何だ 外で待ってなくてもいいって
言っただろ？
（まゆり）エヘヘ どうだった？
How was it?
Uh, well—
ああ うん
Turns out hypnotherapy
wasn't that big of a deal.
まあ 催眠療法っていっても
大したことはなかったな
He said I'll be fine.
特に問題ないってさ
Really?
本当？
Yeah, but I'll need to keep up
the counseling for a while.
ああ しばらくカウンセリングは
必要みたいだけど
You were right. I'm glad I gave it a shot.
まゆりが言うとおり
受診してみてよかったよ
That's a relief.
（まゆり）よかった
Lately, you seemed to be having it rough.
何か オカリン 最近
ずっと つらそうだったから
Sorry to worry you.
心配かけたな
It's okay.
（まゆり）ううん
Wanna go grab a bite?
飯 食べていくか？　おごるぞ
My treat.
In that case, can we head over to Akiba?
それなら
アキバまで行っていいかな？
Ruka and Faris invited me out a bit ago.
さっき ラインで るか君と
フェリスちゃんに誘われたんだ
Akihabara, huh?
秋葉原(あきはばら)か
That a no?
嫌？
No, let's go.
（岡部）いいよ 行こう
わあっ
Hurray!
よかった
じゃあ みんなにも連絡するね
I'll let those guys know we're coming.
Faris? Guess what?
フェリスちゃん？
あのね あのね…
It's already December.
（岡部）もう 12月か…
It feels like that summer
あの夏から…
was just days ago.
早いな
Um, they said they'd be
waiting here somewhere... Oh!
えっと ここで待ってるって
言ってたんだけど… あ！
Ruka! Faris!
るか君 フェリスちゃん
トゥットゥルー！
Hello, Mayuri.
（るか）こんにちは まゆりちゃん
Oh! It's Kyouma!
（フェイリス）おお 凶真(きょうま)！
It's been a while, Rukako, Faris.
（岡部）しばらくぶりだな
ルカ子(こ) フェイリス
Okabe...
（るか）岡部さん
Kyouma! I missed you, meow!
（フェイリス）
凶真 会いたかったニャ！
Hey! Cut it out!
（岡部）おい こら よせよ
（フェイリス）いいじゃないかニャ
What for, meow?
Kyouma knows he likes it, meow!
凶真とフェイリスの仲だニャン
（まゆり）アハハ…
First off, quit with calling me Kyouma.
（岡部）それから
その“凶真”ってのも やめてくれ
How come?
ニャンで？
黒歴史だからだ
That's from the Dark Past.
Is that what you call the dark ages
kept secret by a cult of medieval wizards?
それは つまり 中世魔術師同盟が
ひた隠しにする暗黒歴史
Not even close.
違う
It's so good to see you again.
何か すごく懐かしいです
I go to the lab from time to time,
but never see you there.
僕 時々 ラボに顔を出すんですけど
岡部さんには会えなかったから
I've been busy with things.
（岡部）いろいろ忙しくてな
Don't tell me you're part
of a secret organization!
まさか！　青の組織による
あのプロジェクトが…
いや 大学のゼミが忙しくてな
No, I'm swamped with college seminars.
Meow?
ニャ～
Plus, club and stuff.
それにサークルとか
ニャニャ！
Meow meow?
Okabe's in a club?
岡部さんがサークル…
Researching UFOs and
mythical creatures and stuff?
ＵＦＯ(ユーフォー)とかＵＭＡ(ユーマ)の
研究をしてるとか？
いや… テニスサークルだ
No, the tennis club.
What?
（るか･フェイリス）ええーっ！
（まゆり）アハハ…
'Cuz my associate professor
at college advises the club.
（岡部）大学のゼミの准教授が
テニスサークルの顧問でな
So now you're doing tennis.
（フェイリス）
それで 凶真がテニス…
Look out Wimbledon, here he comes.
（まゆり）
目指せ ウィンブルドンだね
So, practice is why you've been so busy?
（るか）じゃあ その練習もあって
忙しかったんですね
N-No, it's not exactly that intensive.
（岡部）あっ い… いや
練習は そんなには…
Then what else are you doing, meow?
じゃあ 何してるニャ？
If you must know, g-group dates and stuff.
（岡部）何って
ご… 合コンとか
Group...
（フェイリス）合…
（るか）コン？
...dates?
What?
（２人）ええーっ！
岡部さんが合コン!?
Okabe is going on group dates?
How could you? That hurts! That's pathetic!
ニャンというか
痛いというか痛々しいというか
それを通り越してキモイ！
You disgust me, mister! Disgust me!
そう キモイニャ！
（るか）どういうことですか!?
What's gotten into you?
ひどいこと言うなよ
俺だって普通の大学生なんだぞ
Don't be so mean, guys.
I'm a normal college student, you know.
（フェイリス）堕落ニャ 堕落ニャ
凶真 一体どういうことニャ!?
You're lewd! So lewd!
Explain yourself, Kyouma!
How could you, Okabe?
（るか）ひどいです 岡部さん！
Erm—
（まゆり）あっ 由季(ゆき)さんだ
A message from Yuki!
Something happen?
（フェイリス）何か事件かニャ？
No.
ううん アキバに来てるなら―
She said if I'm around Akiba,
she wants to meet up and show me something.
ちょっと見せたいものがあるから
会えないかって
（まゆり）ラボで
（岡部）あっ…
At the lab.
（まゆり）あ…
（フェイリス）あ…
（るか）あ…
（岡部）あ…
It's fine.
大丈夫だ 行こう
Let's go.
ajemjsfmstyk
CRT Television Workshop
Grr...
ajemjsfmstyk
CRT Television Workshop
（ダル）ぐぬぬぬ…
ajemjsfmstyk
CRT Television Workshop
This calls for war!
（ダル）こんなん 戦争だろ
Commence trolling!
炎上 必至だろ！
リア充滅せＰは
ぼっちの味方じゃなかったのかよ！
"Normies Must Die-P"
wasn't our comrade after all!
You've been married to "Parthenon", you fake!
ぱるてのん氏と夫婦だったって
何なん!?
Dad...
（鈴羽）父さん
（ダル）うおっ！
Whoa! @channel and Twipo
are already filled with flaming!
既に @ちゃんねるも
ついポも炎上中？　しまった！
I'm late to the show! How could I miss this?!
僕としたことが乗り遅れたお
このビッグウェーブに！
ひっ!?
Listen to me, or else.
（鈴羽）話を聞きなさい
（ダル）ひぃーっ！
S-Suzuha! Stop it or daddy will get angry.
す… 鈴羽 やめてくれないと
父さん怒っちゃうぞ
I'm already plenty angry with you.
（鈴羽）
怒られてるのは父さんのほう
Right, sorry...
（ダル）はい すいません
（鈴羽）まったく…
For crying out loud...
All you ever do around here is nap,
play games, and browse the net all day.
１日中ゴロゴロして
食べるかネットかゲームばかり
But researching time machines
takes it all out of me.
（ダル）
でも タイムマシンの研究って
大変なんだよ
Plus, we've got one already,
but you won't let me touch it.
しかも 目の前に本物があるのに
“触っちゃダメ”とか言うし
Because it's one you invented in the future.
（鈴羽）父さんが
未来で開発するものだからね
If you saw it now, it's possible
that it might cause a time paradox.
今の父さんが見たら―
タイムパラドックスが
起きる可能性があるんだよ
Since it's guaranteed that I make it, who cares?
（ダル）
未来の僕が発明するならいいじゃん
Means I can procrastinate now!
明日から頑張る！　キリッ！
I'm telling you, it's time
you worked on it seriously.
（鈴羽）そのためには
今から頑張らなきゃいけないの
（ダル）あう…
Mom always gets mad at you in
the future for saying stuff like that.
未来の父さんも
いつも そんなこと言って
母さんに怒られてた
I'd welcome her wrath if
you know what I mean. Huff huff...
（ダル）叱られるという名のご褒美
ハァ ハァ…
Dad!
父さん！
Please forget I said that.
（ダル）はい 何でもないでござる
（鈴羽）未来の父さんは
いつも言っていたんだよ
There's something you always said in the future.
That this world line was
the worst one imaginable...
ここは最低最悪の世界線だけど―
...but having me was the best
thing that ever happened.
私が誕生したことだけは
最高だって
I came here to convince Uncle Okarin so that
we could somehow change that future.
私は
オカリンおじさんを説得して―
そんな未来を変えるために
ここに来たんだ
And yet, ever since that day,
he hasn't come back here once.
なのに あの日以来―
オカリンおじさん
ここにも来なくなって…
ん？
誰か来る！
Someone's here.
Huh? Could it be Okarin?
（ダル）えっ まさか オカリン？
（鈴羽）違う
No, I hear boots.
ブーツの音… 母さんだ！
It's Mom.
Eh?!
えーっ!?　あっ えっ…
Suzuha, hide!
隠れろ 鈴羽！
Okey-dokey!
オーキードーキー！
（ノック）
（ダル）あ はい どうぞ
Come on in.
Hello!
（由季）こんにちは
（ダル）あっ… 阿万音(あまね)氏
どうしたん？　急に
A-Amane-shi? What brings you here?
Hmm? Mayuri isn't around?
（由季）
あれ？　まゆりちゃんは？
Mayushii? Not yet...
まゆ氏？　今日は まだだけど
I think I got here a bit early.
少し早かったかな？
She said she would meet up with me here.
ここで待ち合わせしようって
さっき
Yeah?
（ダル）そうなん？
Mind if I wait inside?
（由季）
待たせてもらっていいですか？
S-Sure...
（ダル）あっ ああ まあ…
Thank you.
（由季）ありがとうございます
Um, is little sister out and about today?
あの… 今日は
妹さんは お留守ですか？
Huh? Little sister? Whose?
えっ 妹？　誰の？
Whose? Yours...
誰って 橋田(はしだ)さんの…
Mine? All my little sisters exist only in 2D form—
僕？
僕に ２次元以外の妹なんて いな…
Ah! Y-You must mean Suzuha!
あっ！
す… 鈴羽のことでござるか？
Who else would I mean?
（由季）ほかにいるんですか？
あー いや… いない？
Uh, well... Nobody?
（まゆり）トゥットゥルー
（ダル）あっ…
（由季）まゆりちゃん
Mayuri!
トゥットゥルー 由季さん
Yuki!
Meow meow!
（フェイリス）ニャンニャン
Faris and Ruka came too!
フェイリスさんも るかさんも
（ダル）フェイリスた～ん
Faris!
Huh? Ah...
えっ？　あっ…
This place hasn't changed a bit.
（岡部）ここは変わってないな
Okarin!
（ダル）オカリン…
Can I come in?
入っても？
No cases have been reported in Japan
New strain of encephalitis
—hallucinations and memory problems,
（アナウンサー）
幻覚や記憶障害
といったものが―
No cases have been reported in Japan
確認されており…
prompting the Ministry of
Health to urge caution when traveling.
I-It's your own lab, so you don't have to ask.
じ… 自分のラボで 遠慮とかねーよ
I suppose so.
それもそうか
Continuing with the news...
Oh! Your clothes are so cute, Yuki!
（まゆり）
あ～ 由季さん その服かわいい！
Earlier, Russia experienced a magnitude 6 earthquake.
I wanted to show you
'cuz I knew you would say that.
（由季）まゆりちゃんに
そう言ってほしくて着てきたんだよ
Let Faris see it too!
（フェイリス）
うわ～ フェイリスにも見せてニャ
We've got Dk Pepper to drink if you—
（ダル）飲み物はドクペで…
あ ちょっ オカリン！
Wait, Okarin! Where are you going?
ど どこへ？
Where? Just to the toilet...
（岡部）どこって…
いや ちょっとトイレへ
Uh...
（ダル）いや…
（鈴羽）あっ…
んん…
だ… だだ…
（岡部）あ… ん？
（ダル）あう…
（岡部）フゥ…
なっ…
どわあっ
Okarin?!
（フェイリス）オカリン!?
（るか）岡部さん！
Okabe!
（鈴羽）あたたたた…
ああっ
Suzu...
鈴さん
H-Hi there.
ど どうも
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Missing Link
of the
Annihilator
Absolute
Zero
Ta-da!
（２人）ジャーン！
（るか）かわいい！
Very cute!
Me like, meow!
（フェイリス）
いいニャ いいニャ～
A feast for the eyes! I'll have seconds!
（ダル）大好物です
ありがとうございます！
（由季）エッヘヘ～
Hmm? Where's Okarin?
（まゆり）あれ？　オカリンは？
He went with Suzuha to the roof.
鈴羽さんと屋上 行ったよ
They wanted to talk about something.
何か話したいことがあるって
I see...
そっかあ
You didn't have to pretend
like this in the first place.
（岡部）わざわざ隠れなくとも
よかったんじゃないか？
Saying you're Daru's little sister
only made yourself more suspicious.
ダルの妹ということに
してるんだから
逆に怪しまれるだろう？
Yeah, but I didn't think Mom
would wanna get to know me so much.
（鈴羽）そうなんだけど…
母さん 思った以上に
私と仲よくしたがるんだ
Yuki and Daru first met at...
（岡部）由季さんとダルが
初めて顔を合わせたのは…
Summer ComiMa.
（鈴羽）夏のコミマ
She was a cosplay friend of Mayu,
but in time, she started coming here.
まゆ姉さんのコスプレ仲間で
ここに出入りするようになって…
（由季）キャッ
（ダル）うわっ
Owowow...
あいたたた… え？
Eh?
Which is how we met.
（鈴羽）顔 合わせちゃった
Eh?
えっ!?
But you're the one she gives birth to.
Her future daughter.
（岡部）
いずれ自分が産むことになる―
未来の娘…
Maybe she feels something.
何か感じるものがあったのかもな
Dad said he'll explain
everything to her sooner or later.
（鈴羽）
父さんは“いずれ説明する”って
言ってくれてるけど…
But man, Daru and that girl...
しかし 本当にダルが彼女と？
私が ここにいるってことは―
The fact that I'm here means
that future hasn't changed.
少なくとも
その未来は変わってない
（鈴羽）あっ
Such peace...
（鈴羽）平和だね
By the time I'd grown up, you'd only
see scenes like these in photos and videos.
私が物心ついたときには―
もう こんな光景は 写真とか
映像の中にしか存在しなかった
World War III...
（岡部）第３次… 世界大戦
Yeah.
（鈴羽）うん 父さんたちは
タイムマシン開発のことで―
Because Dad and the others
were building a time machine,
we were seen as a rebel organization.
反政府組織と見なされてた
But Daru, Yuki, and you somehow escaped?
（岡部）ダルと由季さんと
３人で逃げていたのか？
No...
（鈴羽）
ううん 母さんは軍の無人機から
私を守ろうとして―
My mom tried to protect me from a military
drone and was mowed down by machine guns.
機銃掃射で死んだから…
I saw her get ripped
to shreds right before my eyes.
この目で
ズタズタにされてく母さんを見た
I was practically bathed in her blood.
全身で母さんの血を浴びた
Uncle Okarin...
オカリンおじさん
All that lies ahead in this world line is hell.
この世界線の行き着く先は
地獄しかないんだ
The conflict over time machines makes
country fight country and many people die.
タイムマシン争奪戦によって
国と国が争い 人がたくさん死ぬ
It's a world of nothing but horror and despair.
恐怖と絶望しかない世界なんだ
The lives of 5.7 billion people
are on the line here.
57億の人の命がかかってるんだ
This future...
未来を
I'm begging you...
お願いだよ
I failed.
Uncle Okarin...
オカリンおじさん
I can't...
（岡部）無理だ
（鈴羽）おじさん！
Uncle!
I've drifted through so many
world lines, I've lost count...
（岡部）俺は何度となく
世界線を漂流してきた
No matter the world line, I've witnessed
time machines toy with everyone's fate.
こことは違う世界線で―
タイムマシンに
運命を翻弄される人たちを…
I've even seen you meet your doom.
お前の結末の１つさえ見てきた
And over and over, it never ends.
何度も何度も繰り返したんだ
Believe me, I learned the
limits of what someone can do.
そして 人にできることには
限りがあると知った
No matter what I try, I'm powerless.
何をしても無力なんだ
But you have changed world lines before.
“既に世界線を変えたことがある”
You said it yourself.
そう言っていたよね おじさん
Uncle...
In that case...
だったら…
It's no use!
（岡部）ダメだ！
You can't just change
the past to switch world lines!
過去改変をして
世界線を移動するのは―
It breaks the rules which govern our universe!
この宇宙の仕組みから
逸脱することなんだ
Humans like us can't just
tamper with the province of God!
人間が手を出していい領域じゃない
神の領域なんだ
The moment we start meddling,
we get punished!
触れれば必ず罰を受けることになる
It's terrible! Enough that you
want to clamp shut your eyes!
残酷な…
目を覆いたくなるような罰を！
Is that your answer?
それが答えなの？
There's still time.
まだ時間はある
I want you to reconsider.
考え直してほしい
I...
私は…
...have not given up.
（鈴羽）諦めないから
In the end, I guess Suzu didn't come back.
（まゆり）
鈴さん 結局 戻ってこなかったね
Yeah...
（岡部）ああ
ケンカしたわけじゃないんだよね？
The two of you didn't fight, did you?
That's not what happened.
（岡部）そういうわけじゃない
I see.
（まゆり）そっか
Whew! It's getting pretty nippy, isn't it?
うう… 一段と寒くなってきたねえ
The lab was so lively for a change, it was fun.
（まゆり）今日は久しぶりに
ラボがにぎやかで楽しかったな
Yeah?
（岡部）そうか
（まゆり）うん
Yup!
Somehow, going to the lab lately
has left me feeling really lonely.
何か最近はラボに行くと
とても寂しい気持ちになってたんだ
Isn't Daru there?
（岡部）ダルがいるだろ？
Yeah...
（まゆり）
うん それに昔は まゆしぃ―
But before, Mayushii used to wait
at the lab all by herself for you.
毎日１人でオカリンのこと
ラボで待ってたから―
That's why I shouldn't feel lonely at all.
全然 寂しいはずないんだけど
I don't know why, but I feel
so lonely it makes me want to cry.
でも 何でか分からないけど―
泣きたくなるくらい
寂しくなるんだ
前は もっと
にぎやかだったのになあって
It's like, it used to be a lot more fun.
It's an illusion.
（岡部）錯覚だ
（まゆり）え？
Eh?
（岡部）錯覚だよ
An illusion.
The only people that ever came
to the lab were you, me, and Daru.
あのラボに出入りしていたのは―
俺と お前と
ダルくらいのものだったろう？
Yeah, you're right.
（まゆり）うん そうだよね
（まゆり）ん？
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
1 New Message
Professor Izaki
Nothing.
1 New Message
Professor Izaki
（岡部）ああ あした アキバで―
1 New Message
Professor Izaki
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
People from Viktor Chondria University
are giving a seminar in Akiba tomorrow.
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
ヴィクトル･コンドリア大学の
セミナーがあって
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
Regarding tomorrow's seminar
We're all going out for some drinks. If
you're free, would you care to join us?
I was hoping to talk with their professor,
but I guess they're all out drinking.
その前にゼミの教授と
話しておきたかったんだが
みんなで集まって
飲んでるみたいなんだ
I see!
（まゆり）そっかあ
You're like a full-fledged normie now.
すっかり リア充さんだねえ
Mayushii will be fine by herself.
まゆしぃは １人でも大丈夫だよ
（岡部）そうか じゃあ 悪いけど
Okay.
Sorry to ditch you.
Cheers!
（学生たち）乾杯！
Artificial Intelligence Revolution...
（岡部）人工知能革命…
Viktor Chondria University.
ヴィクトル･コンドリア大学
アレクシス･レスキネン教授か
Professor Alexis Leskinen.
Viktor Chondria
Brain Science Institute Chief Researcher
あいつのいた大学…
Viktor Chondria
Brain Science Institute Chief Researcher
That's... the college she went to.
Viktor Chondria
Brain Science Institute Chief Researcher
（岡部）ううっ…
I think... I'm dying.
（紅莉栖(くりす)）私… 死ぬのかな
I don't want to die...
死にたく… ないよ
（岡部）ひっ… ひっ…
うっ… うっ…
ひっ…
あっ うあああ…
（岡部）ううっ… くっ…
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Hey, you.
（真帆(まほ)）ちょっと あなた
ん？　えっ…
I'm talking to you.
（真帆）そこの君
（岡部）あっ…
ん？
（真帆）
スタッフルームって どこかしら？
Which way is the staff room?
（岡部）あ…
Huh?
（岡部）ああ…
（真帆）ん？
Uh, this is a college seminar conference...
あっ ここ
大学のセミナー会場だけど
Of course I know that!
そんなの分かってるわよ！
It's the same thing, over and over...
もう何度も何度も…
Over and over?
（岡部）何度も？
You're the fourth person
to tell me that since coming here.
この場所に来てから
それ言われるの―
あなたで４回目なの
Viktor Chondria University...
“ヴィクトル･コンドリア大学
脳科学研究所”
Brain Science Institute.
Oh, I get it. You found this and—
ああ 分かった
拾ってくれたん…
（真帆）それも４回目！
Fourth time to hear that too!
んっ
Viktor Chondria University has...
（岡部）
ヴィクトル･コンドリア大学の…
...middle schoolers?
中学生？
If you're gonna be dumb, do it elsewhere.
寝ぼけるのは夜にして！
There's no university
that takes middle schoolers.
大学に中学生がいるわけないでしょ
21 years old?
（岡部）21歳…
In other words, I'm a full-grown woman!
（真帆）つまり立派な成人女性よ
Not in middle school, not elementary
school, and not preschool either!
中学生でも小学生でも
幼稚園児でもなく！
Got a problem?
何か？
But... Never mind.
しかし… いや…
I was in the wrong.
悪かった
I'm sorry.
謝る
Hmph. Whatever.
フン… まあいいわ
The same thing happens
no matter what country I go to.
どこの国に行っても
同じこと言われるから
Big surprise.
（岡部）だろうな…
Did you say something?
何か言った？
N-No, nothing.
（岡部）い… いや 別に
ハァ…
Uh, it's not that way.
（岡部）あ そっちじゃない
Staff room? Go out that way
and it's the door at the end of the hall.
スタッフルームだろ？
一度 出て そこの通路の扉の奥だ
Thanks.
ありがとう
21 years old, huh?
（岡部）21歳か…
If Daru saw her, he'd shout,
"Legal loli for the win!"
ダルが見たら―
“合法ロリ キタコレ！”とか
叫びそうだな
ハッ！
Kiryu Moeka?
（岡部）桐生(きりゅう)… 萌郁(もえか)!?
Why?
どうして―
Why is Moeka here?
萌郁が ここに!?
No... Not again!
まさか また…
Calm down! This is a beta world line!
落ち着け ここはベータ世界線だ
It's not like that other world line!
あの世界線とは違う！
It's not...
違うんだ
（拍手）
（岡部）ん？　あ…
Is that... the girl from earlier?
（拍手）
あれは… さっきの
（レスキネン）ハイ エブリワン
Hi, everyone.
（真帆）皆さん こんにちは
（レスキネンの英語）
Thank you for attending my seminar today.
本日は私のセミナーに
集まってくださって感謝します
I am Alexis Leskinen from Viktor Chondria
University's Brain Science Institute.
ヴィクトル･コンドリア大学
脳科学研究所の―
アレクシス･レスキネンです
I'm his interpreter and assistant, Hiyajo Maho.
通訳とアシスタントは
私 比屋定(ひやじょう)真帆が務めます
（拍手）
（レスキネンの英語）
Our topic for today is the Artificial
Intelligence Revolution, however...
本日のテーマは
“人工知能革命”としましたが―
Before we get into that, there's
a paper I would like to introduce.
その話に入る前に
１つの論文を紹介したいと思います
（レスキネンの英語）
This paper was published by
a female researcher at our lab.
（真帆）この論文は我が研究所の
女性研究員が発表したものです
Our memories are stored in the cerebral cortex.
More specifically, within the temporal lobe.
人の記憶は大脳皮質―
とりわけ 側頭葉に記憶される―
Memories are retrieved
similarly to flash memory.
フラッシュメモリーのような
ものとして捉えることができます
脳はニューロンと呼ばれる
細胞の間を―
The brain operates by sending
electrical signals between neurons.
電気信号が伝わることで働きます
Ultimately, it is the pattern of these electrical
signals which create and reinforce memories.
極論すれば 記憶は電気信号の
パターンによって蓄積し―
作られているといえます
I regret to say the woman who proposed
this theory passed away at the age of 17.
この理論を提唱した彼女は―
残念ながら
17歳にして故人となりましたが―
But using her theory as a foundation,
we were able to construct a special system.
私たちは その理論を基に
あるシステムの構築に成功しました
That is, a system which
preserves human memory as data.
それが人間の記憶をデータ化して
保存するシステムです
（岡部）ああ…
（真帆）これまでのような
プログラムによる―
Unlike previous programs,
which fall short of possessing identity,
疑似人格を
作り上げるのではなく
we've developed an AI with
data drawn from human memories.
データ化した人の記憶をベースに
人工知能を作り上げる
人間同様の感情と記憶―
It has feelings and memories, just like a human.
An artificial intelligence with a heart.
心を持つ人工知能
The genius of Makise Kurisu and
her theory enabled us to build this system.
天才 牧瀬(まきせ)紅莉栖の基礎理論を基に
構築されたシステム
Without further ado, we would
like to demonstrate said AI.
それが これから
デモンストレーションする人工知能
Amadeus.
（レスキネン･真帆）アマデウス
Saying, "I don't want to know what the weather will be like",
ashita no tenki mo "shiranu mama ga ii to"
I leave my umbrella behind.
kasa wo motazu
Those rain-like tears have been overwtitten by a lie that's far too kind.
namida no ame nara yasashisugiru uso ni kakikaeta
The fragments of sky I kept locked in a box
hako ni tojikometa sora no danpen ga
won't fit into this puzzle of the future.
mirai no puzzle ni hamattekurenai
Endless circular reasoning spews forth noise:
mugenkai no suiron wa noise hakidashite
Logic that could fool even the gods
kami sae mo azamuku logic
Moving onward to that place of promise
yakusoku no ano basho he
Knowing nothing about the universe
bokura wa uchuu mo mada shiranai
We'll open Gate Zero
zero no gate hiraku yo
Everything will be reduced to particles, then restored!
subete wa tsubu to nari saisei suru
When that happens, I'll tie down those parts of your consciousness
sorenara togiresou na ishiki mo
on the verge of breaking.
tsunagitometemiseru yo
And living those same moments, in that same place
ano jikan ano basho de
your "time" will begin
kimi no "toki" ga mouichido
once again!
hajimaru
～